Hello and welcome back. In today's video,
we will analyze Aaaa Lord General
Insurance and why I
see potential in the stock. I recently entered this stock, which
I entered just a few days ago, two-three days ago.
Therefore, in this video,
we will analyze it. We will keep the analysis very
brief and short, as always.
This video is only for the purpose of teaching you
how I
choose my stocks and analyze them. There is
no recommendation for buying or selling in this. You should trade based on your understanding. First of all, as always,
we will come to the technicals later. First, let us take
a look at the fundamentals to see what
its fundamentals say. So,
I have opened the fundamentals of ICS Lombard General Insurance
here. The current P is the
first thing I told you. I
look at the P to see if I am
buying any overvalued company. So, first of all, let us look at
its P ratio chart, the
average, which you must be seeing.  Its median PI
is around 46-47-46.2 and currently
it is trading at PI of 40-40.4. The rest of the
EPS chart which is in the background also fluctuates a bit in the middle. If you
look at it normally, it is on the growth side and is
in a growing trend. So, I do
not see any such red flake here. Its EPS is
doing well and for now the PI of the company is
quite good, meaning it is a good valuation PI
company, it is not overvalued as such.
Otherwise, even if it is not in a good valuation, then also
it is not such a big thing but still if I am
buying a very overvalued company and I see its PI in the beginning, then I
analyze it further in that manner with that mindset only.
But because the PI was good, then
you can move ahead with confidence. So,
if I move ahead, first of all I
come to its quarterly results.
You would be seeing its quarterly sales ranging from Rs.
2995 crores to Rs.
5251 crores, so it is currently at an all-time high
in September, it is higher than last September
and also from the last quarter, from June, so
its sales are growing very consistently
and the same consistency is there
in its profits as well. Overall, if you
look at it now, its profits are at an all-time high. It
declined a bit from 610 to 6465 crores here, perhaps because of that
its EPS also decreased.
This growth that is visible here around 2022,
this was just a slight downfall of the company around 2022,
not in terms of its sales but in terms of its profit,
but overall, if you look at it now, it has come
back to its all-time high and its
track is going well,
compared to the last quarters and
also compared to the quarters of last year, so
its profit tax is currently 764 crores
and net profit is also 577 crores, that too the
highest. If we look at the yearly sales, then the yearly sales
So it is very clearly visible that
starting from sales of 3500, the company has now reached 19000 crores
in early sales,
that too its trailing 12
months, which is also the highest, 19000
crores sales and if we look at the last March, then
also 17800 crores, so this year it will report its sales
around 19000, around 19-20 lakhs or more at the
end of this financial year, which is
all positive news, there is
no red flag as of now, the company is very easily
increasing its sales, increasing its profit margin,
not the profit margin, but very easily the
company is increasing its sales,
increasing its profits and its profit before
tax is also 2300 crores which
is the highest till date and this 1757 crores is also its
highest till date in the yearly so all
time high sales, all time high profit
before tax net profit all  Some of them have their
highest till now and then they come down, so
I did not see anything special in it on the balance sheet, hence we will not discuss it, the
rest comes to the share holding pattern, the
share holding pattern, almost
from the beginning till now, meaning the promoter, there has
not been much dip, it is
around 48, right now since around 2021, its
promoters' holding is at 48, which has not reduced till now, a
little fluctuation in this point keeps happening, the
rest of the public
's share holding has recently reduced from June 2023
to September 2023, so it is
from 11.7 to 11.11%, now the public holds
which is a positive sign
in my view that apart from the weak ad,
some strong hands are buying it,
like FI increased its stake to 37 in it,
DI also increased its stake to 41, which
means that it increased its stake from 31,
so FIDS increased its stake in it
in this quarter and the public's stake has reduced,
so obviously  The thing is that when big players are
entering, now they too will
need an exit, so they will take exit at a lower price or at a higher
price, so
keeping all that in mind, the overall look of the
company seems positive as of now, the overall look of the company which
we have seen till now is very brief, I am
discussing things with you, now
if you go to its chart once, this is
my entry symbol on the chart where I
took entry because I was hoping that it will give a
breakout from here and it did happen, it is
not necessary that this happens every time because
even before this there were chances of it giving a breakout
but it did not give, let
me discuss what this breakout was about first, but
before that I will tell you that the price at which it is trading right now
i.e.
1411, its last time price
was in November-December of 2019, that is, in 2019, if
you look at its sales of 2019,
in 2019, its sales were 11000 and
of 1000  It had a net profit, but now
its sales are around 19,000 and its
net profit is 1,700, which means that all its work has almost doubled,
both its sales and its net
profit, but the share price is
available to you at the same price at which the company
was in 2019, which means there is no change in the share price,
but its sales and profits have
doubled, which again becomes a
positive sign for us that how good the
company is at present. Now let's see if any chart
pattern is forming in it, so a chart pattern was
also forming here, if you follow
this line which I have already drawn here, then here
you have a cup and a
small handle here, then this is a big handle and
this third handle here, that is, it is a cup and
handle pattern, that too with multiple handles.
When multiple handles are in the cup and handle
pattern, then you get a little more share from there also, so in these
multiple handles,
I had taken entry on this handle, which
totally do not think that I had this
idea before the breakout, that here  It will give a breakout but
I had taken it totally at random
because I had funds available and there was no
other better option at that time, so I
took entry in it and that too turned out to be good
and it gave an up move from here, so
if I look at its volume below, if you
look at the volume, then the volume is also quite
good, that is, from where it is confirmed
that there is a breakout, now
where does the candle of the next day fall,
if it falls below the support line of this line, then
it means that the
breakout has not got that confirmation yet, but
if its candle falls above the support line, then it
means that its breakout is
confirmed and the
company will move upwards from here very easily, now
if we consider this as a cup and
consider this as the handle, the smaller part, then we will see
how much potential is there in it, then from the
bottom we will mark from here, so this is
your one part,
how much potential is there in the company at
present, which is from here,
around 9 from the current price, 9 to 10  Around and if
you take a slightly longer term target of this, then
this is your slightly longer term target,
if you move it upwards, then
here
it becomes your
target of the bigger cup handle, which is its depth,
we measure that depth and mark it above, so
that much is its target of that cup
handle pattern, so now if you
want, you can hold it for a short target or for the
target of the bigger cup
handle at 25 or you can hold it till its all-time high, which is around 15 from the current price, by the way,
if you look at it, then the company is
posting good numbers and for a long time the
company is consolidating in this area,
hence the
chances of growth of the company remain full and if
one by one it leaves its consolidation and
comes on its growth track, then the company can be found at
much better levels than this all-time high,
but these are the exit
levels as per your own discretion.
I manage it accordingly, based on the scenario at that time,
or what kind of
numbers the company is posting, the
overall market conditions at that time, and the
opportunities I have at that time.
I will exit from it. For now, I have taken an entry
price. If
I were to tell you my entry price, it is
around 1386. If I were to tell you its first target, it would be
1553. Then the second target would be
around 1627. And the third would be
around 1765. These three targets are
in the very short term, which doesn't seem to take
much time. Still, let's see how much
time it takes.
I had just taken the first entry in it. I thought that if its
breakout fails, then if the
price of the company comes down a little, which
is unlikely to happen much
because there are already multiple handles formed,
so if another handle is formed, then
I would again take another entry and
sit in it.
Currently, I have placed
around 2% of my portfolio in this stock.  It is
also very important to keep in mind
how much weightage of your portfolio you
give to a stock and how much interest you have on that stock. The only thing that I had was that much
funds
available, so I allocated
around 2% of my portfolio to this stock. So let's
see how it
moves. I hope you learned something from this video
and the rest of the performance is in
front of you, how it will
move in the future, you should keep an eye on that. For now,
I think that retracing after a breakout is a
very normal thing. It
can retrace again and come to support and
then make a move. But let's see
if it achieves its target of 9-10 before the retracement,
then maybe
I will take the same exit, but that will
depend on the scenario at that time. So, that's all
for today in this video.
In the next video, we will analyze some other
stock. I hope you like the
way I
pick my stocks very briefly. Very brief.  By doing the
analysis, I am able to show very little part of it in the video.
Actual
analysis takes a little more time
and is a little more in-depth, but
if you are starting initially, then
you can start with this much. You
can keep analyzing in this way.
Rest buying and selling is your own understanding.
While watching my video, you should
not take any buying or selling decision. Thank
you, bye-bye, take care.